<resources>
    <string name="app_name">BloodPressure</string>
    <array name="stringLang" translatable="false">
        <item>English</item>
        <item>Français</item>
        <item>भारत</item>
        <item>Indonesia</item>
        <item>日本</item>
        <item>Brazil</item>
        <item>Tiếng Việt</item>
        <item>한국인</item>
        <item>Türkiye</item>
        <item>España</item>
        <item>Italia</item>
        <item>Deutsch</item>
    </array>
    <array name="valueLang" translatable="false">
        <item>en</item>
        <item>fr</item>
        <item>hi</item>
        <item>in</item>
        <item>ja</item>
        <item>pt</item>
        <item>vi</item>
        <item>ko</item>
        <item>tr</item>
        <item>es</item>
        <item>it</item>
        <item>de</item>
    </array>


    <string name="signature">Signature</string>
    <string name="crazy">Crazy</string>
    <string name="melt">Melt</string>
    <string name="run">Run</string>
    <string name="lazy">Lazy</string>
    <string name="diet">Diet</string>
    <string name="nightmare">Nightmare</string>
    <string name="right">Right</string>
    <string name="left">Left</string>


    <string name="ENGLISH" translatable="false">English</string>
    <string name="JAPANESE" translatable="false">日本</string>
    <string name="KOREAN" translatable="false">"한국인 "</string>
    <string name="FRENCH" translatable="false">Français</string>
    <string name="ITALIA" translatable="false">Italia</string>
    <string name="GERMAN" translatable="false">Deutsch</string>
    <string name="VIETNAM" translatable="false">Tiếng Việt</string>
    <string name="INDONESIA" translatable="false">Indonesia</string>
    <string name="BRAZIL" translatable="false">Brazil</string>
    <string name="TURKEY" translatable="false">Türkiye</string>
    <string name="SPAIN" translatable="false">España</string>
    <string name="INDIA" translatable="false">भारत</string>
    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>
    <string name="info">Info</string>
    <string name="setting">Setting</string>
    <string name="back">Back</string>
    <string name="next">Next</string>
    <string name="let_start">Let\'s Start!</string>
    <string name="skip_for_now"><![CDATA[>> Skip for now <<]]></string>
    <string name="title_tool">Blood Pressure Tool</string>
    <string name="content_tool">You can track the Blood Pressure easily and exactly on report.</string>
    <string name="title_health">Graph and Health Report</string>
    <string name="content_health">See the change of your health in every bar graph on it.</string>
    <string name="title_pressure">Blood Pressure Information</string>
    <string name="content_pressure">Give you useful knowledge about blood pressure.</string>
    <string name="max">Max</string>
    <string name="tracker_title">Tracker</string>
    <string name="systolic">Systolic</string>
    <string name="diastolic">Diastolic</string>
    <string name="pulse">Pulse</string>
    <string name="mmhg">(mmHg)</string>
    <string name="language_title">Language</string>
    <string name="normal_blood_pressure">Normal Blood Pressure</string>
    <string name="elevated_blood_pressure">Elevated Blood Pressure</string>
    <string name="high_blood_pressure_stage_1">High Blood Pressure - Stage 1</string>
    <string name="high_blood_pressure_stage_2">High Blood Pressure - Stage 2</string>
    <string name="dangerous_high_blood_pressure">Dangerously High Blood Pressure</string>
    <string name="blood_pressure_type">Blood Pressure Type:</string>
    <string name="got_it">Got it!</string>
    <string name="less_120"><![CDATA[< 120]]></string>
    <string name="and">AND</string>
    <string name="less_80"><![CDATA[< 80]]></string>
    <string name="in_120_to_129">120-129</string>
    <string name="more_130">130+</string>
    <string name="or">OR</string>
    <string name="more_80">80+</string>
    <string name="more_140">140+</string>
    <string name="more_90">90+</string>
    <string name="more_180">180+</string>
    <string name="condition_normal">SYS &lt; 120 and DIA &lt; 80</string>
    <string name="condition_elevated">SYS 120-129 and DIA &gt; 80</string>
    <string name="condition_high_1">SYS 130+ or DIA 80+</string>
    <string name="condition_high_2">SYS 140+ or DIA 90+</string>
    <string name="condition_dangerously">SYS 180+ or DIA 120+</string>
    <string name="date_time"><![CDATA[Date & Time]]></string>
    <string name="save">Save</string>
    <string name="bp_note">BP Notes</string>
    <string name="edit_add">Edit/add</string>
    <string name="history">History</string>
    <string name="edit_instruction">Long press and drag to reorder</string>
    <string name="add_new">Add new</string>
    <string name="add_note">Add Note</string>
    <string name="cancel">Cancel</string>
    <string name="max_20_character_instruction">Maximum 20 characters.</string>
    <string name="hint">Please enter something</string>
    <string name="ok">OK</string>
    <string name="edit">Edit</string>
    <string name="delete_confirm">Delete confirm</string>
    <string name="delete_instruction">Are you sure to delete this record?</string>
    <string name="delete">Delete</string>
    <string name="new_record">New Record</string>
    <string name="dupplicate_note">This note is existed</string>
    <string name="setting_title">Setting</string>
    <string name="export_file_setting">Export as file</string>
    <string name="feed_back_setting">Feed back</string>
    <string name="privacy_policy">Privacy policy</string>
    <string name="rate_us">Rate us</string>
    <string name="share">Share</string>
    <string name="info_title"><![CDATA[Info & Knowledge]]></string>
    <string name="info_1">Some basics about blood pressure</string>
    <string name="info_2">Table to determine the levels of blood pressure</string>
    <string name="info_3">Factors that increase the risk of high blood pressure</string>
    <string name="info_4">Symptoms and complications of high blood pressure</string>
    <string name="info_5">DASH diet for people with hypertension</string>
    <string name="info_6">High blood pressure in pregnancy causes and ways to prevent it</string>
    <string name="info_7">Lower blood pressure through regular exercise every day</string>
    <string name="feed_back_instruction">Please send us some feedback!</string>
    <string name="feed_back_instruction_2">Let us upgrade better functionality and experience for this app. Thanks very much!</string>
    <string name="hint_feedback">Feed back or suggestion</string>
    <string name="the_best_we_can_get">The best we can get ;)</string>
    <string name="oh_no">Oh No!</string>
    <string name="so_amazing">So Amazing!</string>
    <string name="we_like_you_too">We like you too!</string>

    <string name="ask_for_rate">We are working hard for a better user experience. We’d greatly appreciate if you can rate us.</string>
    <string name="expressive_bad">We’re sorry you had a bad experience. Please leave us some feedback.</string>
    <string name="expressive_normal">We would like the opportunity to investigate your feedback further. </string>
    <string name="expressive_bad_a_little">We understand you are not happy with the service you received. Please leave us some feedback.</string>
    <string name="expressive_good">Thank you so much for the wonderful review.</string>
    <string name="expressive_best">Thank you so much for taking the time to leave us your review.</string>
    <string name="rate_on_google_play">Rate On Google Play</string>
    <string name="maybe_later">Maybe Later</string>
    <string name="rate_us_button">Rate Us</string>
    <string name="please_rate">Please rate!</string>
    <string name="min">Min</string>
    <string name="average">Average</string>
    <string name="all_history">All History</string>
    <string name="info_title_1">Some basics about blood pressure</string>
    <string name="info_1_content_1">High blood pressure is a chronic disease where the pressure of the blood against the walls of the arteries is too high. If blood pressure is elevated for a long time, it will put a lot of pressure on the heart, becoming the cause of many serious cardiovascular complications such as: cerebrovascular accident, heart failure, coronary heart disease, myocardial infarction. heart,... However, you can absolutely prevent or treat high blood pressure. Early detection and choosing a heart-healthy lifestyle can prevent high blood pressure from damaging your health.</string>
    <string name="info_1_title_2">What is blood pressure?</string>
    <string name="info_1_title_1">Introduce</string>
    <string name="info_1_content_2">Blood pressure is the pressure exerted on the walls of the arteries to bring blood from the heart to the tissues of the body. Blood pressure is created by the force of contraction of the heart muscle and the resistance of the artery walls. Systolic blood pressure, or systolic blood pressure, is the highest blood pressure in the blood vessels. Systolic blood pressure is the force of blood on the arteries when the heart contracts (the heart is in contraction). Indicated as the greater or upper number in the blood pressure reading. Systolic blood pressure usually varies with age, usually between 90 and 140 mmHg. Diastolic pressure, also known as diastolic blood pressure, is the lowest blood pressure in the blood vessels that occurs between contractions of the heart. Diastolic pressure is the force of blood against the artery walls when the heart relaxes (the heart muscle is relaxed). Indicated as the lower or lower number in the blood pressure reading. Diastolic blood pressure ranges from 50 to 90 mmHg.</string>
    <string name="info_1_title_3">How to determine high blood pressure?</string>
    <string name="info_1_content_3_top">Although it can cause many dangerous complications, the symptoms of high blood pressure are not obvious. The patient may have one or more of the following:\n \u25CF Breathe shallowly.\n \u25CF Headache, dizziness, tinnitus, loss of balance.\n \u25CF Nosebleed.\n \u25CF Chest pain, heart palpitations, palpitations, shortness of breath.\n \u25CF Dizzy.\n \u25CF Eyes blurred.\n \u25CF Red face, nausea, vomiting.\n \u25CF Hematuria.\n \u25CF Insomnia.\n Because there is no one symptom that is considered characteristic of the disease, the most accurate way to know if you have this disease is to have your blood pressure checked regularly at a medical facility or use a blood pressure monitor at home.</string>
    <string name="info_title_2">Table to determine the levels of blood pressure</string>
    <string name="info_2_title_1">Define Blood Pressure</string>
    <string name="info_2_content_1">To determine your blood pressure numbers, you can see the blood pressure category below:</string>
    <string name="info_2_title_2">1. Normal Blood Pressure</string>
    <string name="info_2_content_2">A blood pressure reading below 120/80 mmHg is considered within the normal range. If your results fall into this category, stick to good heart-healthy habits like eating a balanced diet and exercising regularly.</string>
    <string name="info_2_title_3">2. Elevated Blood Pressure</string>
    <string name="info_2_content_3">The systolic reading is between 120 and 129 mmHg and the diastolic reading is less than 80 mmHg. During this stage, doctors usually don\'t treat high blood pressure with medication. Instead, doctors give guidelines that encourage lifestyle changes to improve health.</string>
    <string name="info_2_title_4">3. High Blood Pressure - Stage 1</string>
    <string name="info_2_content_4">Blood pressure always hovers around 140/90 mmHg or higher. At this stage of high blood pressure, doctors may prescribe medication in combination with changes in eating and living habits.</string>
    <string name="info_2_title_5">4. High Blood Pressure - Stage 2</string>
    <string name="info_2_content_5">Blood pressure always fluctuates between 130-139 systolic or 80-89 mmHg diastolic. At this stage, you should change to a healthier lifestyle and consider taking more blood pressure medications.</string>
    <string name="info_2_title_6">5. Dangerously High Blood Pressure</string>
    <string name="info_2_content_6">This stage of hypertension requires medical attention. If your blood pressure reading suddenly exceeds 180/120 mmHg, wait five minutes and then check your blood pressure again. If your readings are still abnormally high, you need to contact your doctor or go to the nearest medical facility to check.</string>
    <string name="info_title_3">Factors that increase the risk of high blood pressure</string>
    <string name="info_3_content_1">Anyone can develop high blood pressure, but there are several factors that can increase your risk: <b>\n• Life style</b> \nSome lifestyle habits can increase the risk of high blood pressure, such as inactivity, high use of stimulants, stress and anxiety, a diet too high in salt... <b>\n• Family history</b> \nMany observational studies show that children born in families with parents with high blood pressure in particular or other cardiovascular diseases in general will have a higher risk of having it than the general population.  <b>\n• Age/gender</b> \nAge is an unmodifiable risk factor for hypertension. However, knowing how to limit other factors that increase blood pressure will help stabilize blood pressure sustainably over time. Before age 55, men are more likely to develop high blood pressure than women. After age 55, women are more likely to develop it than men.  <b>\n• Race</b> \nAccording to many studies, high blood pressure is more common in African-American adults.<b>\n• Weight</b> \nPeople who are overweight or obese are more likely to have high blood pressure than those who have effective weight control <b>\n• There are also some other factors such as side effects of drugs during treatment, comorbidities, improper blood pressure measurement...</b></string>
    <string name="info_4_content_1">Heart rate: The heart beats abnormally fast, causing the patient to often feel palpitations.</string>
    <string name="info_4_content_2">Headache: Increased pressure in the walls of the blood vessels affects the pressure inside the cranium, leading to headaches that cannot be relieved even with medication. In some cases, the pain can increase with intense intensity, the patient needs immediate emergency assistance.</string>
    <string name="info_4_content_3">Blushing: This phenomenon occurs when the blood vessels in the face dilate. However, this sign is not a typical symptom, because the blushing reaction can be caused by many different causes such as hot, cold weather, spicy food, etc. However, you should not be subjective. as this can be a warning sign of abnormal blood pressure readings.</string>
    <string name="info_4_content_4">Vision: Increased pressure can damage blood vessels in the eye. The most common complications are retinal diseases, more serious can cause patients to lose vision completely. In addition, the optic nerve can also be affected if the high blood pressure persists.</string>
    <string name="info_4_content_5">Some other symptoms: shallow breathing, nausea, shortness of breath, insomnia, etc.</string>
    <string name="info_4_content_6">What are the dangerous complications that high blood pressure can cause?</string>
    <string name="info_4_content_7">Heart failure: The heart has to work too hard to pump blood to the body, causing the heart to enlarge and weaken over time.</string>
    <string name="info_4_content_8">Kidney failure: The blood vessels in the kidneys narrow, causing kidney failure.</string>
    <string name="info_4_content_9">Stroke, myocardial infarction: The risk of atherosclerosis in people with high blood pressure is very high. The hardening of the blood vessel wall, the plaque attached to the blood vessel wall can peel off and drift away, leading to blockage of smaller blood vessels causing stroke, heart attack.</string>
    <string name="info_4_content_10">Aneurysm: High blood pressure can cause aneurysms when ruptured aneurysms will cause bleeding, the most dangerous is cerebral hemorrhage, causing high mortality.</string>
    <string name="info_4_content_11">Brain complications: Brain hemorrhage, cerebral infarction, memory loss…</string>
    <string name="info_4_content_12">Metabolic syndrome: Metabolic disorders of the body such as sugar metabolism disorders causing diabetes, fat metabolism disorders causing hyperlipidemia, protein metabolism disorders causing increased uric acid leading to gout…</string>
    <string name="info_4_content_13">Retinal hemorrhage: Blood vessels in the eye burst, causing eye pain, blurred vision, and more dangerously, blindness.</string>
    <string name="info_4_content_14">High blood pressure is also a risk of causing glaucoma, also known as a headache (severe headache, eye pain, blurred vision, if not treated promptly, it will lead to blindness).</string>
    <string name="info_5_content_1">DASH (short for Dietary Approaches to Stop Hypertension) is a healthy diet designed to help treat high blood pressure or prevent it. It\'s a diet based on studies funded by the National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute (NHLBI). The DASH diet encourages you to reduce salt in your diet and eat foods rich in nutrients that help lower blood pressure, such as potassium, calcium, and magnesium.</string>
    <string name="info_5_content_2">The DASH diet:</string>
    <string name="info_5_content_3">Proper protein supplementation: should only use low-fat meats, seafood, low-fat or fat-free milk, ... or some plant proteins such as soybeans, peanuts, chia seeds, ... to limit the amount of cholesterol and acid. unhealthy saturated fat such as fat, animal organs, packaged and processed foods, etc.</string>
    <string name="info_5_content_4">Fiber: you should eat a lot of dark green vegetables such as water spinach, kale, spinach, etc. In addition to vitamins and antioxidants, these foods also contain a lot of Potassium, Magnesium, which is very good for your digital health. abnormally high blood pressure measurement.</string>
    <string name="info_5_content_5">Starch: Replace refined starch with whole grains such as brown rice, oats, glutinous rice, etc.</string>
    <string name="info_5_content_6">Limit foods high in saturated fat. These foods include fatty meats, full-fat dairy products, and tropical oils like coconut, palm kernel, and palm oil.</string>
    <string name="info_5_content_7">Limit sugary drinks and sweets.</string>
    <string name="info_5_content_8">Limit salt: Eating a lot of salt makes the body need to replenish water, increasing pressure on blood vessels. Therefore, only light dishes should be processed, not a lot of spices (salt, fish sauce, soup powder, ...).</string>
    <string name="info_5_content_9">Some other notes: drink enough water, give up the habit of using coffee, alcohol, tobacco, should lose weight if the body is obese, ...</string>
    <string name="info_5_content_10">Following the DASH eating plan and maintaining a healthy lifestyle at the same time will help lower your blood pressure.</string>
    <string name="info_6_content_1">1. What is gestational hypertension?</string>
    <string name="info_6_content_2">Pregnancy-Induced Hypertension is an increase in blood pressure that occurs after the 20th week of pregnancy and returns to normal 6 weeks after delivery. High blood pressure in pregnancy is mild at about 140-159/90-109 mmHg, severe when ≥160/100 mmHg.</string>
    <string name="info_6_content_3">2. Causes of high blood pressure in pregnant women</string>
    <string name="info_6_content_4">The disease can be caused by the following main causes: "</string>
    <string name="info_6_content_5">Nutrition during pregnancy is not scientific, pregnant women eat too salty;</string>
    <string name="info_6_content_6">Pregnant women are not physically active, do not take care of the pregnancy properly;</string>
    <string name="info_6_content_7">Sudden weather changes, too hot or too cold;</string>
    <string name="info_6_content_8">Pregnant women over 35 years old;</string>
    <string name="info_6_content_9">Pregnant women with diabetes or related diseases that lead to high blood pressure complications during pregnancy.</string>
    <string name="info_6_content_11">3. Know the symptoms of high blood pressure during pregnancy</string>
    <string name="info_6_content_12">Common signs of high blood pressure in pregnant women appear in the second half of pregnancy include:</string>
    <string name="info_6_content_13">Swollen feet and hands;</string>
    <string name="info_6_content_14">Sudden weight gain;</string>
    <string name="info_6_content_15">Visual disturbances (blurred vision, double vision, transient loss of vision,...);</string>
    <string name="info_6_content_16">Nausea, vomiting;</string>
    <string name="info_6_content_17">Severe headache, epigastric pain, retrosternal chest pain and shortness of breath.</string>
    <string name="info_6_content_18">4. How to prevent high blood pressure in pregnancy?</string>
    <string name="info_6_content_19">Doctors said that if gestational hypertension is not detected early and treated promptly, it will lead to many dangerous complications for both mother and baby. To avoid unfortunate incidents, before planning a pregnancy, women should note the following issues:</string>
    <string name="info_6_content_20">Avoid pregnancy and childbirth at an advanced age;</string>
    <string name="info_6_content_21">Overweight women need a weight loss plan before pregnancy;</string>
    <string name="info_6_content_22">Follow a healthy diet, eat lots of fruits and vegetables, etc. to reduce the risk of gestational diabetes. If you already have diabetes, pregnant women need to control their blood sugar well before and during pregnancy;</string>
    <string name="info_6_content_23">Exercise in moderation before and during pregnancy under the guidance of your doctor. Pregnant women diagnosed with pre-eclampsia need gentle exercise, and it is not recommended to stay in bed for a long time.</string>
    <string name="info_7_content_1">Strength training through sports activities is an indispensable part of the process of lifestyle change and treatment of hypertension. However, depending on the stage, patients with hypertension should pursue some appropriate exercises to balance their blood pressure levels.</string>
    <string name="info_7_content_2">Normally, it takes 2-3 months of regular exercise for blood pressure to change positively. So you need to persevere in practice and avoid discouragement.</string>
    <string name="info_7_content_3">During stage 1 and 2 hypertension, you can combine and alternate many different exercises to avoid boredom.</string>
    <string name="info_7_content_4">Going to the park or finding friends to practice with is an effective measure for people with high blood pressure, while helping you keep your spirits up and enjoy social life.</string>
    <string name="info_7_content_5">Warming up before exercise and relaxing after exercise play an important role, helping you avoid injury and giving your body time to balance blood pressure.</string>
    <string name="info_7_content_6">Always breathe evenly, breathe deeply while exercising. Holding your breath or breathing irregularly can cause your blood pressure to rise and cause muscle pain.</string>
    <string name="info_title_7">Lower blood pressure through regular exercise every day</string>
    <string name="info_title_6">High blood pressure in pregnancy causes and ways to prevent it</string>
    <string name="info_title_5">DASH diet for people with hypertension</string>
    <string name="info_title_4">Symptoms and complications of high blood pressure</string>
    <string name="title_notification_1">8 dangerous complications of high blood pressure</string>
    <string name="content_notification_1">Know more about your health</string>
    <string name="title_notification_2">5 efective ways to lower your blood pressure</string>
    <string name="content_notification_2"><![CDATA[Click & Read more]]></string>
    <string name="title_notification_3">5 warning signs of gestational hypertension</string>
    <string name="learn_more">Learn more</string>
    <string name="title_notification_4">7 Effective diets to prevent High blood pressure</string>
    <string name="content_notification_4">Read and apply now!</string>
    <string name="title_notification_5">5 levels of blood pressure and danger warnings</string>
    <string name="content_notification_5">Click and read now</string>
    <string name="title_notification_6">Do you understand blood pressure correctly?</string>
    <string name="title_notification_7">6 factors that increase the risk of High blood pressure</string>
    <string name="content_notification_7">Click and read now</string>
    <string name="title_notification_8">Effective prevention of gestational hypertension</string>
    <string name="content_notification_8">Note and Apply</string>
    <string name="title_notification_9">Doctor\'s advice to improve High blood pressure</string>
    <string name="title_notification_10">Prevent stroke by measuring blood pressure every day</string>
    <string name="title_notification_12">How to Maintain Normal Blood Pressure?</string>
    <string name="content_notification_12">Record blood pressure status daily to track your BP</string>
    <string name="contain_ads">This action can contain ads</string>
    <string name="generating_csv">Generating csv file</string>
    <string name="gen_csv_success">Generate success</string>
    <string name="gen_csv_failed">Generate failed</string>
    <string name="no_sender_found">No provider found</string>
    <string name="must_fill_note">Notes cannot be empty</string>
    <string name="rate_success">Rate success</string>
    <string name="title_4_addition">"Common symptoms "</string>
    <string name="latest">Lastest</string>
</resources>